start with a regular heptagon and draw
another regular heptagon inside with
Area 1 8 of the original this decomposes
the heptagon into eight pieces of size 1
8. one of them a trapezoid at the bottom
represents 1 8. now let's continue this
again on the inner heptagon now we have
another shaded region of 1 8 times 1 8
or 1 8 squared we can continue this
process indefinitely each time we cut up
the heptagon into eight equal area
pieces and take one of them this means
that each piece we have is 1 8 of the
previous 1 8 of the area
if we do this forever we see that this
shaded region now has an area
represented by the sum of the powers of
1 8. but on the other hand we see that
in terms of the full picture this shaded
area is exactly 1 7 of the entire
heptagon therefore the sum of powers of
1 8 is equal to 1 7.